Andreas Poppmeier Resume

Dublin, Ireland | Contact No: 0858298062 andreas.poppmeier2@mail.dcu.ie https://andreas720.github.io/

Bio

A highly motivated individual with a passion for software development and design. I have been actively developing my own projects for the past 2 years and continue to up my skill-set on a daily basis. My core interests are developing apps in Java and Angular 2+. My motivation is to create and deliver quality, intuitive software that other developers and users will want to use with an attention to even the minutest of detail.

Skills

Programming: Java, IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse IDE, JUnit, Spring MVC, REGEX, Git, JIRA, Docker, JDBC

Web Development: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JSON, REST API's, PHP, phpmyadmin, SQL, JSON, Javascript, yaml

Unix: Shell scripting, Unix command line

Other skills: WireShark, VMware, Network protocols, Knowledge of computing hardware (built my own custom PC)

Experience

Astreya @ Google / Equipment Maintenance Technician

OCTOBER 2018 - OCTOBER 2019, Google Barrow Street, Dublin

- Managing hardware and accessory deployment to front line users at Google's European headquarters in Dublin
- Laptop and desktop imaging, deployment and recovery
- Technical maintenance and troubleshooting to support issues
- Contributing to large scale global projects as needed
- Using ticketing systems to report individual work accomplishments and to track Service Level Agreements (SLAs)
- Ensuring audio and visual quality, troubleshooting any issues that may arise and any requests from meeting attendees.

Bloomberg Polarlake / Software Engineer Intern

FEBRUARY 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2017, Harcourt Building, Harcourt Street, Dublin

- Worked within the R&D team in an agile environment
- Use of Eclipse IDE to update and maintain Java applications and develop data products in correlation with Business Analysts to improve products and services.
- Worked with Oracle 12c to create and maintain databases as well as run SQL queries
- Worked with Docker to containerize web services
- Worked with technologies such as Python, XML, XML DOM, Jenkins, Spring MVC, Maven, REGEX

OASIS Group - Information Mgmt. / Data Intern

JUNE 2016 - JAN 2017, Kinsealy Business Park, Dublin

- Use of Salesforce CRM to extract necessary data
- Use of R programming language for data analysis
- Executed SQL gueries to display relevant data to be used within R
- Assisted in the revamp of the business website

Education

Dublin City University / Bsc. Enterprise Computing

SEPTEMBER 2014 - JUNE 2018, Glasnevin, Dublin

Modules included but are not limited to:

- 1. Fundamentals of Computer Programming
- 2. Networks and Internet & Managing Enterprise Computer Systems
- 3. Web Programming
- 4. IT Mathematics
- 5. Developing Internet Applications
- 6. Software & Systems Testing

Full list of modules can be viewed at: https://bit.lv/32U6V3f

St. Fintan's High School / Leaving Certificate

Obtained my Leaving Certificate with all higher-level subjects including higher-level mathematics.

Projects & Courses

<u>University of Helsinki Programming with Java MOOC</u> - An online open course that makes use of the IntelliJ IDE using an embedded plug-in which allowed me to refresh on the basics of computer programming, algorithms and object-oriented programming using the Java programming language.

<u>CRUD Application</u> - Built a basic CRUD Application using Angular & Spring Boot that displays a list of cars. It allows you to edit the cars, and then shows an animated gif from GIPHY that matches the car's name.

<u>Building Your First Web App with HubSpot Academy</u> - The online course is designed to teach how to build a web application from scratch; it allowed me to get familiar with using GitHub, Heroku, and node.js, as well as how to stylize my application and integrate an API.

Interests

- Team member at Clontarf F.C.
- Technology
- Reading
- Occasional chess player
- Running
- Swimming
- Music & guitar
- Cycling & bicycle mechanics